Once every hundred years, the Star Festival
lights up the skies over the Mushroom Kingdom.
- Mario! You made it!
- Wouldn't miss it, Princess.
Peach has been waiting all week.
She says a shooting star landed in the castle garden.
It's not a star, Mario. It's... alive.
Look, it's glowing.
The whole sky just turned dark.
That's not part of the festival, is it?
Airships! The castle is under attack!
Everyone, get inside!
Mario! Help! The whole castle —
it's being pulled into the sky!
Hold on, Peach! I'm coming!
Nobody steals a castle on my watch!
He jumped for the chains, brave and stubborn as ever,
and the dark ships swatted him away like a firefly.
And the little star from the garden
followed him down through the cold and the dark.
Wake up. Wake up, mister mustache.
You fell a very long way.
Where... where am I? The castle!
Peach! Where is she?
Far away. Very far. But you're lucky —
I'm a Luma, and Lumas know the way between stars.
A talking star. Sure. Why not.
Okay, little guy. Take me to her.
First you need power. Star power.
Catch the sparkles, grow the wings. Watch!
Whoa! I'm flying! Luigi is never
going to believe this!
This is the Comet Observatory.
It sails wherever the comets sail.
And this is Rosalina.
She watches over all of us.
Welcome, Mario. The Lumas told me about you.
You're searching for someone you love.
Someone took her. Ships out of a black sky.
I don't even know who.
I do. And I'm sorry.
Because it means he's found the Grand Stars again.
Rosalina, the observatory's engines are cold.
Without the Grand Stars we drift like driftwood.
Then we make a deal. I bring back your Grand Stars,
and you sail me to wherever Peach is.
So the plumber survived the fall.
GWAHAHA! Good. I wanted an audience.
Bowser. I should have known.
Where is she, you overgrown turtle?
Somewhere above your head, little man.
I'm done stealing kingdoms. I'm building my own.
A galaxy of my very own, powered by the Grand Stars,
with a throne at the center of everything.
And your princess gets the best seat in the house —
right next to the reactor.
You can still stop this, Bowser.
Give back the stars. Let her go.
Stop? I'm just getting started.
Kamek! Show our guest the exit.
Three Grand Stars, back in their cradles.
The observatory hums like it's young again.
You've done more than I hoped, Mario.
But the last star burns at the heart of his fortress sun.
Then that's where we sail.
All engines, straight into the fire.
There's something you should know first.
About why Bowser's new galaxy can never hold.
A galaxy built on stolen stars collapses inward.
He isn't building a kingdom. He's building a black hole.
Mario! You came! You actually
flew across the universe!
Told you. Nobody steals a castle on my watch.
Now let's get you out of here.
It's too late, look! The fortress sun —
it's folding in on itself!
No! My galaxy! MY GALAXY!
What's happening to my galaxy?!
It was never going to hold, Bowser.
Rosalina tried to warn you. Take my hand!
You'd save ME? After everything?
...You really are the strangest little man.
The little Luma — he's flying into the core!
What is he doing?!
What Lumas are born to do, Mario.
When a star grows up, it becomes a galaxy.
The dark closed like a mouth, and then —
light. A brand new spiral of stars where the hole had been.
The festival's back on. Luigi saved you a seat.
And look — the new galaxy is right overhead.
He's up there somewhere, isn't he? The little guy.
Shining away.
They always come back, Mario.
Stars never really go out.